Oscar Hernandez Baute

Computer Engineering

+1 786 827 8028 Miami, Florida oscarhernandezbaute@gmail.com https://oscarhdezbaute.github.io/

SUMMARY Computer engineering, full stack .NET developer with more than 14 years of experience in C# & .NET technologies and frameworks. Also experience in working with SCADA, HMI, PLC and DCS programming. With teamwork and freelance skills with high work performance and years of general experience in the industry. Experience including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debugging and maintenance.

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering

University of Cienfuegos "Carlos Rafael Rodríguez" | 2003 - 2008, Cienfuegos, Cuba.

EXPERIENCE

CEDAI Inc - Industrial Automation

Full Stack .NET Developer | 2015 - 2023

- Leader of five full stack developers working in C# technology.
- Analysis of requirements with clients in the industrial, financial and health sectors.
- Design, development and testing of several applications back-end and front-end in the sectors mentioned above, using Asp.NET, C#, NET CORE, MVC, WebForms, Xamarin Forms, WinForms. EF, Nhibernate, API, RESTful Service.
- Front-end & back-end applications maintenance.
- Technical support to clients, experience with continuous integration and continuous delivery.
- Troubleshooting.

CEDAI Inc - Industrial Automation

Full Stack Developer | 2008 - 2015

- Front-end and back-end applications developer with Typescript, Javascript, HTML5. C#, Net Framework 3.5, 4.0 Asp.NET WebForms, MVC, Winforms, Razor, NHibernate, SQL Server.
- Data transport structures such as JSON, XML.
- Building layout with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.
- Desktop & web applications maintenance.
- Troubleshooting.

ABILITIES

C# | C++ | ASP.NET | NET CORE | MVC | Entity framework | NHibernate | ADO.NET | WebForms | WinForms | Xamarin Forms | REST | API | XML | XAML | HTML | JSON | Javascript | Boostrap | ¡Query | CSS | SQL Server | Transact-SQL | Stored procedures | MySQL

RUP | UML | XP methodology | GIT

https://oscarhdezbaute.github.io/ PORTFOLIO

LANGUAGES Spanish: Native

English: B1 level